TV를 볼 때에는 밝은 방에서 적당히 떨어져서 보도록 해!
While you're watching the television...
Selama menonton acara ini
...be sure to keep your distance and watch in a well-lit room!
pastikan berada di jarak yang cukup dan di ruangan yang terang!
Plan
Webdiver Production Committee
Original Plan
Ishikawa Hiroto
Dennou Boukenki
Series Composition
Chief Director
Sekijima Mayori
Okajima Kunitoshi
Character Design
Takahashi Naruyo
Concept Design
Color Scheme
Moriki Yasuhiro
Kawami Takuya
Production Designer
Director of Audiography
Composite Director
Iwase Eiji
Tanaka Hideyuki
Nagaushi Yutaka
Music
Music Producer
Music Collaboration
Hayashi Yuzo
Kumada Kazuo
Television Tokyo Music
Opening Theme
Lyrics
Composer/Arrangement
Oikawa Neko
Hirama Akihiko
Song
Columbia Japan
Production Collaboration
Animation Production
Animation Producer
AEON (We've)
Kachihide Yuki
Nomura Hiroshi
Producer
Iwata Makiko (TV Tokyo)
Yamazaki Tatsuji
Director
Negishi Hiroshi
Production
나오키. 데리트로스님께서 새로운 명령을 내리셨다.
Naoki. Lord Deletloss has sent a new order to us.
Naoki, Yang Mulia Deletloss telah mengirimkan perintah baru.
근데, 드라그온, 넌 아직...
But, Dragwon, you're still...
Tapi, Dragwon, kau kan masih...
걱정 마라.
Don't worry.
Jangan khawatir.
나에게 전달된 임무를 대신 수행할 수 있는 녀석이 있으니.
There are guys under me who can execute the order instead.
Di sini ada orang yang akan menggantikanku untuk menjalankan perintah ini.
이것이 내가 데리트로스님께서 받은 위대한 힘이다.
This is the great power that Lord Deletloss awarded to me.
Inilah kekuatan dashyat yang dipercayakan Yang Mulia Deletloss kepadaku.
가라! 블랙 재규어온! 유우키 켄토를 쓰러뜨리고 글라디온을 고립시켜라!
Go! Black Jaguaron! Take Yuuki Kento down and isolate Gladion!
Pergilah, Black Jaguaron! Kalahkan Yuuki Kento dan musnahkan Gladion!
각오해라, 켄토.
Prepare yourself, Kento.
Bersiaplah, Kento.
D
To
거
Da
Torn
검
Dar
Tornad
검으
Dark
Tornado
검은
Dark T
Tornado Ke
검은 ㅎ
Dark To
Tornado Keg
검은 호
Dark Torn
Tornado Kege
검은 회
Dark Torna
Tornado Kegela
검은 회오
Dark Tornad
Tornado Kegelapa
검은 회오리
Dark Tornado!
Tornado Kegelapan!
검은 회오리!
Dark Tornado! T
Ke
검은 회오리! ㅍ
Dark Tornado! Tar
Ken
검은 회오리! 표
Dark Tornado! Targ
Kento
검은 회오리! 표저
Dark Tornado! Targe
Kento ya
검은 회오리! 표적
Dark Tornado! Targete
Kento yan
검은 회오리! 표적으
Dark Tornado! Targeted
Kento yang
검은 회오리! 표적은
Dark Tornado! Targeted K
Kento yang Di
검은 회오리! 표적은 ㅋ
Dark Tornado! Targeted Ke
Kento yang Diin
검은 회오리! 표적은 케
Dark Tornado! Targeted Ken
Kento yang Diinc
검은 회오리! 표적은 켄ㅌ
Dark Tornado! Targeted Kento
Kento yang Diincar
검은 회오리! 표적은 켄토
[[=10.nref2]]
[[=10.nref2_1]]
[[=10.nref2_2]]
[[=13.nref3]]
[[=13.nref3_1]]
[[=13.nref3_2]]
[[=13.nref4]]
[[=13.nref4_1]]
[[=13.nref4_2]]
[[=13.nref5]]
[[=13.nref5_1]]
[[=13.nref5_2]]
잘 들어라, 나오키. 블랙 재규어온은 글라디온에게 쓰러진 재규어온의 사악한 기운을 실체화시킨 것.
Listen, Naoki. Black Jaguaron is the realization of Jaguaron's Evil Aura who was taken down by Gladion.
Dengar, Naoki. Black Jaguaron adalah perwujudan nyata dari sisi jahat Jaguaron yang telah dikalahkan oleh Gladion.
나와 너의 정신으로 조종할 수 있다.
It can be controlled with the combination of our soul and senses.
Ia dikendalikan dengan gelombang kekuatan jiwa kita berdua.
알았어.
Got it.
Aku mengerti.
우리 명령을 따라라.
Obey our will.
Patuhi kehendak kami.
블랙 재규어온.
Black Jaguaron.
나팔꽃: 위성 "아사가오" (朝顔, 조안)
Morning Glory: a satellite named Asagao (朝顔, literally Morning Face)
Morning Glory: sebuah satelit bernama 'Asagao' (朝顔), diambil dari nama bunga.
큰, 큰일입니다! 기상 관리 위성 나팔꽃의 시스템에 정체불명의 바이러스가 침입했습니다!
Big problem! An unknown virus has intruded into the weather controller system, Morning Glory!
Ce-celaka! Sebuah virus yang misterius telah menyusup ke sistem satelit pengendali cuaca, Morning Glory!
바이러스라고?
Virus?!
Apa kau bilang? Virus?!
급속히 기상 관리 프로그램이 변조되고 있습니다.
The weather controller program is being altered in a high speed!
Virus itu sedang menimpa program pengendali cuaca dengan kekuatan tinggi!
풍신: 위성 "후우신" (風神)
Wind God: a satellite named Fuushin (風神)
Wind God: sebuah mesin pengendali cuaca, diterjemahkan dari Fuushin (風神)
풍신이 움직이기 시작했습니다!
The Wind God has started to move!
Wind God tiba-tiba bergerak!
뭐요? 풍신은 아직 건설 중일 텐데!
What?! Isn't Wind God still under construction?!
Tidak mungkin! Bukankah Wind God masih dalam tahap pemasangan?!
90% 완성되었습니다. 기상 기계로 기능은 문제없습니다!
It's 90% completed. Its weather control function is working properly!
Tapi sudah selesai 90%. Tidak ada masalah dalam fungsinya sebagai pengendali cuaca.
스크린에 띄워 주시오.
Please put it on the screen.
Coba tampilkan di layar.
네.
Got it.
Baik.
대체 무슨 일인가.
How could it turn out like this...?
Kenapa bisa begini...?
풍신은 나팔꽃에서 명령을 전달받습니다.
Wind God moves according to what Morning Glory commands.
Wind God bergerak atas komando dari Morning Glory.
설마...
Don't tell me...
Jangan-jangan...
빨간 블록 위에~ 뛰고~
Let's step on the red ones~! Heave ho~!
Ayo cepat, kita injak yang merah~! Ayo! Injak yang merah~!
잠깐! 마모루! 기다려!
Hey! Mamoru, wait!
Hei! Mamoru. tunggu aku!
서두르지 않으면 영화관에 늦을 거야!
But, if we don't hurry, we might be late for the movie!
Tapi, kalau kita tidak buru-buru, nanti nonton filmnya bisa terlambat!
그렇게 빨리 가지 않아도 돼!
It'll be fine even without rushing like that!
Tidak usah lari-laripun masih akan sempat!
켄토가 기다리고 있을 텐데!
Kento and the others must have waited for us!
Kento dan yang lainnya sudah menunggu kita dari tadi!
저거 뭐야, 아오이?
What's that, Aoi?
Aoi, apa itu?
어?
Huh?
Hah?
UFO야! 우주인이 침략한다!
It's an UFO! The aliens are invading!
Itu kan UFO! Kita diserang oleh alien!
설마!
No way!
Tidak mungkin!
안돼!
No!
Apa ini?!
따라온다!
It's following us!
Dia mengejar kita!
아오이하고 마모루 늦네! 뭔 일이라도 있나.
Aoi and Mamoru are being late! I wonder what's got to them.
Aoi dan Mamoru lama sekali! Kemana saja mereka, ya?
뭐지?
What's happening?
Ada apa itu, ya?
유우키 군. 저거다!
Yuuki. That's the one!
Taketo, coba kau lihat itu!
방향을 바꿨습니다! 어디를 향한 걸까요?
It changed its path! I wonder where it is heading to.
Arahnya berubah! Kira-kira, kemana tujuannya?
계속 따라오고 있어!
It's still following us!
Dia masih saja mengejar!
정말 끈질겨!
How persistent!
뭔 일이지?
What's going on?
Apa yang terjadi?
아오이!
Aoi!
아오이! 마모루!
Aoi! Mamoru!
켄토!
Kento!
거기 있군!
There you are!
Dia di situ!
켄토!
Kento!
아야!
Ouch!
Aduh!
뭔 일이람.
What's this?
Apa-apaan ini?
켄토가 회오리 안에!
Kento is in the tornado!
Kento terkurung dalam angin puyuh itu!
켄토!
Kento!
괜찮아, 아오이?
Are you okay, Aoi?
Aoi, kau tidak apa-apa?
이건 데리트로스 짓이겠지. 젠장, 어떻게든 여기서 탈출하지 않으면...!
This must be Deletloss' work again. Damn, I need to get out from here!
Ini pasti ulah Deletloss. Sial, aku harus berusaha keluar dari sini!
아오이!
Aoi!
할아버지! 아저씨! 저 안에 켄토가...
Grandpa! Mr. Yuuki! Kento is inside that thing...
Kakek! Paman! Kento ada di dalam situ...
켄토가?
Kento is?
Kento?
안에 갇혔어요!
He's trapped inside!
Dia terkurung di dalam angin puyuh itu!
나가는 게 불가능해요!
He can't escape from there!
Dia tidak bisa keluar dari sana!
바이러스가 풍신을 완전히 지배해버린 것인가.
Did the virus has taken total control of Wind God?
Apa mungkin Wind God sudah sepenuhnya dikendalikan oleh virus?
빨리 뭐라도 하지 않으면 켄토가...!
If we don't do something, Kento will..!
Kalau tidak segera melakukan sesuatu, bisa-bisa Kento...!
응. 둘 다 물러서 있어!
Yeah. Stand back, you two!
Iya. Mundurlah kalian!
아저씨!
Mr. Yuuki!
Paman!
저거다!
That's it!
Aku bisa menggunakannya!
그래, 되겠다!
Good, it worked!
Nah, bisa jalan!
기다려라, 켄토!
Just you wait, Kento!
Tunggulah, Kento!
뭐야?!
What the?!
Tidak mungkin!
이런...
Darn...
Ternyata gagal...
유우키 군!
Yuuki!
Taketo!
아저씨!
Mr. Yuuki!
Paman!
괜찮나?
Are you okay?
Apakah kau terluka?
전 괜찮습니다.
I'm all right.
Aku baik-baik saja.
켄토...
Kento...
Brought to you by Subdiver
풍신은... 오!
The Wind God is... Oh!
Bagaimana Wind God... Oh!
나팔꽃으로 명령을 전달받고 있으니 월드 링크 관리국에서 직접 접속할 수 있지 않을까.
Since it's under the control of Morning Glory,
Karena dia bergerak dengan dikendalikan dari satelit Morning Glory, makanya kita tidak bisa mengaksesnya dengan antena stasiun pengendali World Link.
shouldn't we be able to access it directly from World Link Administration Center?
나팔꽃의 회로를 끊으면 풍신은 멈출 것이다!
If we cut off the circuit of Morning Glory, Wind God will stop!
Kalau kita bisa memutuskan sirkuit Morning Glory, maka Wind God akan berhenti!
가능성이 있습니다!
That might be possible!
Mungkin itu bisa kita lakukan!
컴퓨터는 내 자동차 안에 있다. 할 텐가, 아오이?
There's a computer inside my car. Will you do it, Aoi?
응.
Yes.
Iya.
켄토. 힘내!
Kento, hang in there!
Bertahanlah, Kento!
켄토!
Kento!
글라디온...
Gladion...
프로그램 완료. 송신!
Program complete. Now sending!
Program selesai. Jalankan!
저런!
No way!
Kenapa begini?!
왜?
What happened?
Ada apa?
바이러스가 외부에서의 접속을 전부 막았어.
The virus has disabled all incoming connection from outside.
Sepertinya virusnya telah memprogram agar semua akses yang datang dari luar tidak bisa masuk.
어쩌지...
What should we do...
Bagaimana ini...
박사님.
Professor.
Profesor.
뭐, 그냥 그 나팔...어쩌고를 부수어버리면 될 텐데.
Well, why don't we just crash the mor-something instead?
Kalau begitu, kenapa kita tidak hancurkan Mor-apalah itu saja?
그래! 그거다! 옛날 언젠가 사용됐던 위성이 나팔꽃 근처에 있을 게다.
Yes, that's it! There should be a satellite that was once used nearby the Morning Glory!
Benar juga! Itu dia! Kalau tidak salah, ada satelit lama yang terletak tidak jauh dari Morning Glory!
이걸로 나팔꽃을 충돌시키는 것이다.
Crash that satellite to Morning Glory.
Tabrakkan satelit itu ke Morning Glory.
두 위성의 속도와 궤도를 입력하면 시뮬레이션해서 충돌시킬 정확할 시간을 알아낼 수 있니?
Can you input their orbital position and relative speed,
Bisakah kau menginput posisi orbit dan kecepatan dari kedua satelit itu,
and create a simulation to determine the perfect timing to make them crash?
dan membuat simulasi untuk menentukan timing yang tepat agar mereka bertabrakan?
해 볼게.
I'll try.
Akan kucoba.
잘 하는구나! 빨리 이 프로그램을 송신해!
Aren't you good at this? Now upload this program quickly!
Bagus sekali! Sekarang, cepat jalankan programnya!
응!
Alright!
Baik!
켄토!
Kento!
정신 차려, 켄토.
Pull yourself together, Kento.
Bertahanlah, Kento.
켄토!
Kento!
아빠. 아, 아빠! 위에!
Dad. Dad! Up there!
Ayah. A-ayah! Di atas!
모두 괜찮니?
Is everyone okay?
Kalian baik-baik saja?
응, 왠지.
Yeah, somehow.
Iya, baik-baik saja.
위기일발이었어.
That was really close.
Kita nyaris saja celaka.
아빠! 모두! 고마워! 살았어!
Dad! Everyone! Thanks! I'm saved!
Ayah! Teman-teman! Terima kasih! Aku tertolong!
켄토! 어디 가니?
Kento! Where are you going?
Kento! Kau mau pergi kemana?
매지컬 게이트에 플러그 잇!
To Magical Gate, Plug It!
Menuju Magical Gate, Plug It!
걱정했어뾰꼬! 무사해서 다행이야뾰꼬!
I was worried-pyoko! Good to see you safe-pyoko!
Kami khawatir-pyoko! Syukurlah kau baik-baik saja-pyoko!
글라디온! 당장 출격 가능해?
Gladion! Can we sort out immediately?
Gladion! Bisa, kan, kita berangkat sekarang juga?
항상 괜찮지만, 켄토, 그 몸으로 괜찮겠어?
I'm always ready, but will you be okay with such condition?
Aku siap kapan saja, tapi, apakah kau mampu dalam kondisi seperti itu?
걱정 마! 다친다고 해봤자 난 더 강해지는걸!
Don't worry! More I get hurt, more I get excited!
Tenang saja! Semakin disakiti, maka semangatku akan semakin besar!
좋아! 출격이다! 켄토! 적은 코스모 에이리어의 배틀 필드에 있다!
Good then! We shall sort out! The enemy is at the battlefield in Cosmo Area!
Baiklah! Kita berangkat, Kento! Musuh kita ada di area pertarungan di Cosmo Area.
웹다이브! 글라디온!
Webdive! Gladion!
긴급 발진 대기중.
Emergency dispatch, standby.
Siap untuk diluncurkan.
글라디온, 출동.
Gladion, shoot!
웹체인지! 글라디온, 파이터 모드!
Webchange! Gladion, Fighter Mode!
너는!
You're...!
Kau...!
저건!
That's...!
Itu, kan...!
재규어온!
Jaguaron!
뭔 일이야?! 왜 재규어온이?!
Why?! Why is Jaguaron there?!
Kenapa?! Kenapa Jaguaron...?!
아니. 잘 봐라, 켄토. 저건 재규어온이 아니다!
No. Look again, Kento. That's not Jaguaron!
Bukan. Lihat baik-baik, Kento. Itu bukan Jaguaron!
그, 그러고 보니,
S- so it's not him...
B-bukan ya...
조사 결과가 나왔어뾰꼬. 저건 블랙 재규어온이야뾰꼬.
Analysis complete-pyoko. That's Black Jaguaron-pyoko.
Analisa data sudah keluar-pyokoDia Black Jaguaron-pyoko.
블랙 재규어온?
Black Jaguaron?
드라그온이 재규어온에게서 빼간 사악한 기운으로 만들어 낸 거야뾰꼬!
That was made with the Evil Aura that Dragwon took from Jaguaron-pyoko!
Dia dibuat dari energi jahat yang diambil dari Jaguaron oleh Dragwon-pyoko!
우리가 회수한 데이터처럼 사악한 기운으로도 웹나이트를 만들 수 있었는가.
Just like how we can recover datas, even Webknights can be created from an Evil Aura...
Seperti halnya kita bisa memulihkan data, jadi dari energi jahatpun, bisa dibuat Webknight, ya?
온다! 켄토!
It's coming, Kento!
Dia menyerang, Kento!
피해, 글라디온!
Dodge it, Gladion!
Menghindarlah, Gladion!
다시 똑바로 서고!
Let's rebuild our stance!
Bersiaplah menghadapi serangan berikutnya!
글라디온, 젠장, 개틀링 버스터 과녁이 될 셈이야?
Gladion, damn, are you going to be the target of Gatling Buster?
Gladion, sial, dia terus menyerang kita dengan Gatling Buster!
움직임이 빨라서 다음 동작을 예측할 수 없어뾰꼬!
I cannot predict his next movement because it's too fast-pyoko!
Gerakannya terlalu cepat sehingga sulit untuk ditebak-pyoko!
이대로라면 불리해...
This is bad...
Kalau terus begini, bisa gawat...
가짜놈! 여기까지다!
Hey, you imposter! Stop it right there!
Hei, gadungan! Cukup sampai di situ!
재규어온이다! 진짜 재규어온이 왔어!
That's Jaguaron! The real Jaguaron has come!
Itu Jaguaron! Jaguaron yang asli telah datang!
글라디온, 가자!
Gladion, let's do it!
Gladion, ayo kita lakukan!
웹체인지! 재규어온, 어택 모드!
Webchange! Jaguaron, Attack Mode!
글라디온, 개틀링 모드!
Gladion, Gatling Mode!
개틀링 버스터!
Gatling Buster!
해냈다!
We did it!
Berhasil!
고마워. 덕분에 살았어, 재규어온.
Thank you. We won't be able to make it without you, Jaguaron.
Terima kasih. Kau sudah menolong kami, Jaguaron.
당연히 해야 할 일이었어!
You don't have to thank me for that!
Itu bukan masalah besar!
어쨌든 정말 위기일발의 상황이었어뾰꼬.
Anyway, it was really close-pyoko.
Tapi, tadi benar-benar nyaris saja-pyoko.
그래도 끈질기게 버텨냈잖아, 글라디온?
But, we've gotten used to that already, haven't we, Gladion?
Kalau cuma seperti itu, sih, kita sudah biasa. Benar kan, Gladion?
데리트로스가 직접 켄토를 노리다니, 이대로라면 켄토가 위험해.
Deletloss is targeting Kento directly. Kento is in a grave danger.
Deletloss mulai mengincar Kento secara langsung. Kalau dibiarkan begini terus, Kento bisa celaka.
칫, 켄토놈. 운 좋긴.
Tch. Dammit, Kento. What a lucky bastard.
Cih. Dasar Kento. Dia benar-benar lagi beruntung.
성급할 필요 없다. 블랙 재규어온은 쓰러졌을지 모르지만 다음이 있지.
Don't be hasty. Black Jaguaron might be defeated, but we still have the next chance.
Tidak perlu buru-buru. Biar Black Jaguaron sudah kalah, tapi masih ada kesempatan berikutnya.
우리가 글라디온과 켄토를 몰아 최후의 일격을 날릴 거야.
We will make Kento and Gladion cornered, then we shall finish them off!
Kita buat Kento dan Gladion terdesak, dan yang akan menghabisi mereka adalah kita!
재밌겠어.
Sounds like fun.
Aku sudah tidak sabar.
Screenplay
Kishima Nobuaki
Storyboarding
Staging
Oda Mihiro
Voice Actor
Yuuki Kento
Gladion
Arisugawa Aoi
Asaba Naoki
Kobayashi Yumiko
Sugita Tomokazu
Kikuchi Shiho
Takeuchi Junko
Karon
Kaida Yuki
Voice Actor
Yuuki Taketo
Ookura Masaaki
Arisugawa Professor
Tobita Nobuo
Sanjouji Mamoru
Kurokawa Nami
Voice Actor
Jaguaron
Kawashima Tokuyoshi
Dragwon
Kawada Shinji
Employee A (Susumu)
Suzumura Ken'ichi
Ending Theme
Lyrics
Composer
Suzuki Kisaburo
Arranger
Kyouda Seiichi
Singer
Columbia Japan
Production Cooperation
Animation Production
AEON (We've)
Subtitle
Subdiver
ファン字幕
サブダイバー
Production
Thank you for watching!
Preview for Next Episode
모니터에서 이상한 소리가 울려 퍼져.
A strange melody is echoing from the monitor.
Sebuah nyanyian misterius terdengar dari monitor.
오늘은 참 졸려.
I'm desperately sleepy today.
Hari ini aku ngantuk sekali.
이대로라면 자 버릴 것 같아...
I might as well sleep now...
Bisa-bisa aku langsung tertidur...
어? 왜 다들 열받은 것 같지?
Huh? Why are everybody burning mad?
다이버랜드가 이상하리만치 잔잔해.
Diverland becomes awfully silent.
Diverland tiba-tiba menjadi sangat sunyi.
드라그온이 남겨진 우릴 가지고 놀고 있어.
Dragwon's evil hand is toying around with us who are the only ones left.
Dan kami yang masih bertahan dipermainkan dengan tangan jahat Dragwon.
전뇌모험기 웹다이버의 다음 이야기!
Next episode of Dennou Boukenki Webdiver!
Di episode Dennou Boukenki Webdiver selanjutnya!
Stay tuned
for the
next story!
Thanks for watching! - Subdiver
See you at http://subdiver.soreepeong.com/ !